Guide to the New Dramatists Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
New Dramatists records
1931-1996
YCAL MSS 690
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
153.75
(132 boxes) + 12 broadside folders
The records date from the organization's founding in 1949 and include administrative correspondence, application files, financial and fund-raising records, internal reports, audio recordings and transcripts of guest lectures and craft discussions, audio recordings of board meetings and play readings, photographs, scrapbooks holding clippings about the organization, artwork and production materials for New Dramatists newsletters and publications, and other files related to the group's management and activities, including the ScriptShare program. Prominent in the collection are more than seven hundred play and screenplay scripts which formed a script library at the New Dramatists' office. They include drafts and final scripts by playwrights Robert Anderson, James Baldwin, Sydney Chandler, James Leo Herlihy, Romulus Linney, John McGowan, Lanford Wilson, and John Wolfson, among others, some of which are annotated with production notes. Unique to the collection are a group of whimsical doodles created by theatre celebrities and a set of autographed sign-in boards from the New Dramatists' annual spring luncheons (1980-1996). With the exception of one play script from 1931, the records primarily date from the organization's founding in 1949 through the 1988-1989 season.
New Dramatists, Inc
Anderson, Robert, 1917-2009
Baldwin, James, 1924-1987
Chandler, Sydney
Herlihy, James Leo
Linney, Romulus, 1930-2011
McGowan, John, 1894-1977
Wilson, Lanford, 1937-2011
Wolfson, John
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from New Dramatists, Inc., on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 1999.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 128: Restricted until 2050. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Boxes 129-132 (sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Separated Materials
Mary K. Frank's personal scrapbook documenting her production of two Alan Paton plays in 1956 and 1964 was also received with the New Dramatists Records; it was cataloged separately in 2013.
New Dramatists, Inc.
New Dramatists, Inc., was founded in New York in 1949 by Michaela O'Harra in association with Howard Lindsay, Richard Rodgers, Russel Crouse, Oscar Hammerstein II, John Golden, Moss Hart, Maxwell Anderson, John Wharton, Robert E. Sherwood and Elmer Rice. The organization has since its beginning awarded seven-year resident fellowships to playwrights enabling them to use dedicated writing and performance spaces to develop their scripts through readings and workshops, with the encouragement and assistance of fellow playwrights, directors, stage managers, professional actors, and the New Dramatists support staff. Among the administrators of the organization were Thomas G. Dunn, director from 1981-1990, and Susan Gregg, director-in-residence and, later, director of script development and marketing.
For further information, see the organization's website, http://newdramatists.org/.
Scope and Contents
The records include administrative correspondence, application files, financial and fund-raising records, internal reports, audio recordings and transcripts of guest lectures and craft discussions, audio recordings of board meetings and play readings, photographs, scrapbooks holding clippings about the organization, artwork and production materials for New Dramatists newsletters and publications, and other files related to the group's management and activities, including the ScriptShare program. Prominent in the collection are more than seven hundred play and screenplay scripts which formed a script library at the New Dramatists' office. These include drafts and final scripts by playwrights Robert Anderson, James Baldwin, Sydney Chandler, James Leo Herlihy, Romulus Linney, John McGowan, Lanford Wilson, and John Wolfson, among others, some of which are annotated with production notes. Unique to the collection are a group of whimsical cartoons and doodles created by theatre celebrities and a set of autographed sign-in boards from the New Dramatists' annual spring luncheons (1980-1996). With the exception of one play script from 1931, the records primarily date from the organization's founding in 1949 through the 1988-1989 season.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Script Library, 1931-1985. II. Administrative Files, 1949-1996.
Dramatists -- United States -- 20th Century; Theater -- United States; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Mechanicals (camera-ready copy) -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Scrapbooks -- United States -- 20th Century; Scripts (documents) -- United States -- 20th Century; Dramatists -- United States -- 20th Century; Anderson, Robert, 1917-2009; Baldwin, James, 1924-1987; Chandler, Sydney; Dunn, Thomas G.; Gregg, Susan, 1943-2009; Herlihy, James Leo; Linney, Romulus, 1930-2011; McGowan, John, 1894-1977; Wilson, Lanford, 1937-2011; Wolfson, John; New Dramatists, Inc
- Script Library, 1931-1985; Series I; 39.17; (32 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  Scope and Contents
  The series holds more than seven hundred play and screenplay scripts by authors affiliated with New Dramatists. The material once formed a script library which was available for use by the public as well as by the organization's staff and fellows.
  - Anonymous
    - One and Only, undated (Box 1)
  - Abuba, Ernest
    - An American Story, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Adams, James and Jova, Henri
    - Fly by Night (musical), 1956 (Box 1)
  - Adams, James
    - Swamp Song (play with music), 1958 (Box 1)
  - Adelman, Louis
    - Coke Night on the Corner (2 copies), 1952 (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, Keith
    - Free the Mountain Lion, undated (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Eric
    - Bad Guys, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Only Connect (3 copies), 1982 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Robert
    - Free and Clear (2 copies), undated (Box 1)
    - Love Revisited, undated (Box 1)
    - Silent Night, Lonely Night, undated (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Walt
    - Leaf in the Wind, undated (Box 1)
  - Andrews, William
    - The Undressing of a Nude, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Appell, Don
    - Lullaby (Manuscript), 1953 (Box 1)
    - Lullaby (Published) (Box 1)
  - Appleman, H. A.
    - Accounting for Murder, undated (Box 1)
  - Appleman, Herbert
    - The Fortune Hunters, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Heyday (musical), 1972 (Box 1)
    - A Terrible Saint, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Apstein, Theodore
    - Illusion, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Armstrong Jr., Robert
    - Move Back the Stars, undated (Box 1)
  - Aulicino, Armand
    - The Family Circle, undated (Box 2)
    - The Portable Street, undated (Box 2)
  - Baldwin, Edward and Fedoroff, Alexander
    - People in Glass Houses
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Fedoroff, Alexander, Box 9
  - Baldwin, James
    - The Amen Corner (2 copies), undated (Box 2)
  - Baldwin, Joseph
    - Bronson Leaf, 1957 (Box 2)
    - A Cry of Stones, 1956 (Box 2)
    - State University, undated (Box 2)
  - Balf, Miriam and Rubio, Emery
    - The Jewelry of Dale
      See: Rubio, Emery, Box 25
  - Barlow, Anna Marie
    - The Bicycle Riders, undated (Box 2)
    - Cold Christmas, undated (Box 2)
    - Ferryboat, undated (Box 2)
    - Hunky Dory Book by Anna Marie Barlow; Music by Charles Strouse; Lyrics by Lee Adams (musical), 1974 (Box 2)
    - The Meeting, undated (Box 2)
    - The PH Deed, undated (Box 2)
    - Wind Chimes, undated (Box 2)
  - Barrows, Robert Guy
    - A Beast in the Forests, undated (Box 2)
    - Bivouac at Lucca, undated (Box 2)
    - A Coin to Cross Acheron, 1957 (Box 2)
    - The Enemy Way, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Honkytonk on a Paper Piano, undated (Box 2)
  - Baumbach, Jonathan
    - A Longer Age Endure, undated (Box 2)
  - Bell, Neal
    - Raw Youth, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Bellak, George
    - The Troublemakers, undated (Box 2)
    - The Victim, undated (Box 2)
  - Belville, Lance
    - Plain Hearts, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Scott and Zelda: The Beautiful Fools, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Bennet Jr., Walter Allen
    - Ties That Bind, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Berg, Barry
    - Kindly Observe the People, undated (Box 3)
    - The Man Who Drew Circles, undated (Box 3)
    - Nightlight, undated (Box 3)
    - Toussaint, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Best, Charles
    - Gordon Reilly, undated (Box 3)
    - The Kids, undated (Box 3)
    - Love Discovered, undated (Box 3)
    - The Natives by Moonlight, undated (Box 3)
    - The Postal Urge (rough draft), undated (Box 3)
    - Revolt of the Goslings (original version), undated (Box 3)
    - Sam Saved From Success, undated (Box 3)
    - Sharks (act 1-rough draft), 1972 (Box 3)
    - Suspicious People, undated (Box 3)
    - A Young Man's Guide to the Upper Air (3 plays-Escape of the Salesman, Goodbye Klapp, Another Part of the Sofa), undated (Box 3)
  - Bettenbender, John
    - Heir of the Serpent, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Ride a Cock Horse, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Biel, Nicholas
    - Gone for a Soldier, undated (Box 3)
    - Sound of the Goose, undated (Box 3)
  - Bigelow, Otis
    - The Lion and the Unicorn, undated (Box 3)
    - My Fair Lady, undated (Box 3)
  - Birnkrantz, Samuel
    - The Little Gondola, undated (Box 3)
  - Blessing, Lee
    - War of the Roses, undated (Box 3)
  - Bosley, James
    - Fun, undated (Box 3)
  - Bovasso, Julie
    - Gloria and Esperanza, undated (Box 3)
  - Breen, Edward
    - Grenade, undated (Box 4)
    - The Trouble with Emily, undated (Box 4)
  - Brewster, Townsend
    - The Cable, undated (Box 4)
  - Bromberg, Conrad
    - A Life in the Family, undated (Box 4)
    - A Round Trip to America, undated (Box 4)
  - Bronner, Edwin
    - The Air-Conditioned Jungle, undated (Box 4)
    - Ghost Story, undated (Box 4)
  - Brown Kenneth
    - The Happy Bar, undated (Box 4)
    - Three Dreams from Dell's Couch, undated (Box 4)
  - Bullins, Ed
    - A Son; Come Home; The Man Who Dug Fish (3 plays), undated (Box 4)
    - Goin' a Buffalo, 1966 (Box 4)
    - The Duplex, undated (Box 4)
  - Burgie, Irving and Mitchell, Loften
    - Ballad for Bimshire
      See: Mitchell, Loften, Box 22
  - Burton, Russell
    - The Man who Lost his Skis, undated (Box 4)
  - Burston, Bud and Sherman, Allan
    - The Golden Touch
      See: Sherman, Allan, Box 26
  - Caldwell, Joseph
    - Clay for the Statues of Saints, undated (Box 4)
  - Capotorto, Carl
    - A Child's Tale, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Mitzi's Glory, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Carlino, Lewis John
    - The Exercise, undated (Box 4)
    - High Sign, undated (Box 4)
    - The Mechanic (screenplay), 1968 (Box 4)
    - Seconds (screenplay), 1964 (Box 4)
    - Telemachus, undated (Box 4)
  - Carter, Robert A.
    - The King is in His Counting House, 1959 (Box 4)
    - Bughouse Square, 1962 (Box 4)
    - In the Aquarium, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Cascio, Anna Theresa
    - Strega or the Witch, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Caton, Michael
    - At the River, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Censabella, Laura Maria
    - Jazz Wives Jazz Lives, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Chandler, Sydney
    - Bridge Into Night, undated (Box 5)
    - The Witness, 1963 (Box 5)
    - Somewhere a Voice is Calling, undated (Box 5)
    - The Last Hours are for Joy, 1959 (Box 5)
    - Games Played While Waiting, 1956 (Box 5)
    - The Rape of Summer, 1959 (Box 5)
    - The Rain is Killing the Summer, 1958 (Box 5)
    - A Psalm for Fat Tuesdays, 1956 (Box 5)
    - Pleasure City, Thy Muddy Waters, 1957 (Box 5)
    - Werner, 1962 (Box 5)
    - The Photographers, 1963 (Box 5)
    - The One-Eyed Man is King, 1958 (Box 5)
    - A Long Way From Home, 1957 (Box 5)
    - Legend, undated (Box 5)
    - The Survivors of Summer, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Chekhov, Anton
    - The Three Sisters, undated (Box 5)
  - Child, Nellise
    - Happy Ending, undated (Box 5)
    - Gwennit the First, undated (Box 5)
    - Bird of Time, undated (Box 5)
    - House of Shame, undated (Box 5)
    - Judith, undated (Box 5)
  - Childress, Alice
    - Man Bearing a Pitcher, undated (Box 5)
    - Mojo, 1970 (Box 5)
    - More than a Notion, undated (Box 5)
    - So Early Monday Morning, undated (Box 5)
    - Trouble in Mind, undated (Box 5)
    - Wedding Band, undated (Box 5)
    - Young Martin Luther King (musical), undated (Box 5)
  - Cizmar, Paula and Gower, Douglas
    - Tough Girls (screenplay), 1984 (Box 5)
  - Clarke, David Ulysses
    - Amnesia, the Beautiful, 1978 (Box 5)
    - Never a Snug Harbor, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Natural Causes, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Mrs. Fiske, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Matrix, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Remarkable Anna, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Lunatics, undated (Box 6)
  - Clarke, William Kendall
    - The General Comes Home, undated (Box 6)
  - Cobin, Harold
    - Annie's Son, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Annie's Corner, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Cohen, Bennett
    - American Music, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Cohen, Edward M.
    - The Last Stage of Labor, undated (Box 6)
    - The Complaint Department Closes at Five, undated (Box 6)
  - Coleman, Val
    - The Devil's Harp, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Comorthoon, James
    - Intercession, undated (Box 6)
    - Every Other Evil, undated (Box 6)
    - And I Detest My Sins, undated (Box 6)
  - Congdon, Constance
    - The State of the Unions: Sunday Morning, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Cooper, Mae and Klein, Grace
    - Maggie, undated (Box 6)
    - The Tender Green, undated (Box 6)
  - Cornish, Roger
    - Thaw: A Russian Melodrama, undated (Box 6)
  - Coudert, Jo
    - Duncan, undated (Box 6)
    - Homebodies (musical), undated (Box 6)
    - Knight and Squire and their Ladies, 1964 (Box 6)
    - The Nearest Way, undated (Box 6)
    - Richard Comes Wednesday, undated (Box 6)
  - Coudert, Jo and Heldt, Marion
    - The Rock Chimney, undated (Box 6)
  - Cowen, Ron
    - Summertree, undated (Box 6)
    - Valentine's Day (musical), 1970 (Box 6)
  - Coyle, J. J.
    - Land Where Our Fathers Died (3 Plays) Country, Family, and God, undated (Box 7)
  - Craig Jr., Richy and McGowan, John
    - Pardon Me! (act one)
      See: McGowan, John, Box 21
  - Crane, Burton
    - Stage-Stricken, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Daglish, Robert
    - If I Live, undated (Box 7)
  - Daugherty, Mick
    - Joy, undated (Box 7)
    - Mano de Lobo, undated (Box 7)
    - The Vicar, undated (Box 7)
  - Davidson, Madeline
    - Ancestor Figures, undated (Box 7)
    - The China Dog, undated (Box 7)
    - A Foreign Sky, undated (Box 7)
  - Davis, Allen
    - Birth, undated (Box 7)
    - Bull Fight Cow, undated (Box 7)
    - Hooks and I's, undated (Box 7)
    - The House of Solomon, undated (Box 7)
    - The Rag Doll, undated (Box 7)
    - Where are All the Pompom Girls?, undated (Box 7)
    - Where the Green Bananas Grow, 1967 (Box 7)
    - A Whiff of Sulphur, undated (Box 7)
  - Dearborn, Elwyn
    - East Side Gladiator, undated (Box 7)
  - Dee, Peter
    - Daughter of a Traveling Lady, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Filigree People (2 copies), 1981 (Box 7)
    - The Fred and Ginger Contest (2 copies) (musical), 1983 (Box 7)
    - Goddesses, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Jacinta, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Jacinta, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Martinique (2 copies), 1982 (Box 7)
    - Midnight Piano, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Quartet (3 copies), 1982 (Box 8)
    - A Sea of White Horses (2 copies), 1976 (Box 8)
    - Steal Prometheus, undated (Box 8)
    - When the Kids Are Away (2 copies), 1981 (Box 8)
  - De Roo, Edward
    - The Cat's Cradle, undated (Box 8)
    - Georgie, 1956 (Box 8)
  - Di Canzio, William
    - Open Heart, undated (Box 8)
  - Dickaman, Kenneth
    - Between Sunsets, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Dizenzo, Charles
    - Disaster Strikes the Home, 1968 (Box 8)
    - The Drapes Come, undated (Box 8)
    - An Evening with Merlin Finch, 1968 (Box 8)
    - The Nixon Show, undated (Box 8)
  - Drake, Alfred
    See: Eager, Edward, Box 8
  - Drexler, Rosalyn
    - The Bed Was Full, undated (Box 8)
    - I'm the Captain, undated (Box 8)
    - The Investigation, undated (Box 8)
    - The Line of Least Existence, undated (Box 8)
    - Softly, and Consider the Nearness, undated (Box 8)
  - Duane, Frank
    - Guitar, undated (Box 8)
    - Jimmy and the River (play with music), 1950 (Box 8)
  - Duberman, Martin
    - The Colonial Dudes, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Groups, undated (Box 8)
    - Visions of Kerouac, undated (Box 8)
  - Duboid, Rene Daniel
    - Panic in Longueuil (2nd Draft) (3 copies), 1984 (Box 8)
  - Dundy, Elaine
    - A Death in the Country; The Drowning (2 plays), undated (Box 8)
  - Dunning, Philip and McGowan, John
    - The Last Song
  - Eager, Edward
    - Man, Beast and Virtue, undated (Box 8)
  - Eager, Edward and Drake, Alfred
    - 76 (musical), undated (Box 9)
  - Elder, Lonne
    - Deadly Circle of Violence (teleplay), 1968 (Box 9)
  - Elman, Irving
    - The World and Arthur Jones, undated (Box 9)
  - Elwell, Robert
    - Joshua, undated (Box 9)
  - Epstein, David
    - Plane Down, undated (Box 9)
    - When this Battle is Over, undated (Box 9)
  - Eric, Elspeth
    - If You Loved Me, 1952 (Box 9)
  - Erickson, David Michael
    - Last Night's Lightning, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Esser, Carl
    - Neighbors (musical), 1970 (Box 9)
  - Esser, Carl Wright
    - The Audition, undated (Box 9)
  - Essex, Harry and Ruscoll, Joseph
    - A Neighborhood Affair, undated
      See: Ruscoll, Joseph, Box 25
  - Falk, Lee
    - Happy Dollar (musical), 1949 (Box 9)
  - Fedoroff, Alexander
    - Day of Grace, undated (Box 9)
  - Fedoroff, Alexander and Baldwin, Edward
    - People in Glass Houses (2 copies), undated (Box 9)
  - Fenn, John
    - A Servant's Christmas (2 copies), 1983 (Box 9)
    - The Lady Knight (2 copies), 1983 (Box 9)
  - Field, Barbara
    - The Education of Paul Bunyan, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Quality Time, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Fleming, Conn
    - Dinner on the Ground (3rd Draft), undated (Box 9)
    - Erogenous Zones; Foreign Organisms; Sexual Candidates (3 Plays), undated (Box 9)
    - An Untitled Play, undated (Box 9)
  - Foote, Horton
    - The Trip to Bountiful, undated (Box 9)
  - Foreman, Richard
    - Angel Face, undated (Box 9)
    - Elephant Steps (musical), undated (Box 9)
    - Good-Bennie, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Harry in Love, undated (Box 9)
    - Trash, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Foreman, Stephen H.
    - The Hunting of Pink Mountain Tinney (screenplay), undated (Box 10)
    - Leave of Absence, undated (Box 10)
    - Moonshot, 1969 (Box 10)
    - Moonshot; The Reliquary of Mr. and Mrs. Potterfield; Passion Play (3 plays), 1969 (Box 10)
    - Harry in Love, undated (Box 10)
    - Moonshot; The Reliquary of Mr. and Mrs. Potterfield (2 plays), 1969 (Box 10)
    - Resolution of Mossie Wax, undated (Box 10)
  - Foster, Gladys
    - About a House, undated (Box 10)
    - Attention, Please!, undated (Box 10)
    - CDX, undated (Box 10)
  - Foster, Paul
    - Elizabeth 1st, 1971 (Box 10)
    - The Madonna in the Orchard, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Fraenekel, Helene
    - Dark Legend, 1953 (Box 10)
    - Three Ring Circus, undated (Box 10)
  - Friedman, Joel
    - The Last Goodbye, 1958 (Box 10)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Lyman, undated (Box 10)
    - You Can Always Do Business with Sylvia, undated (Box 10)
  - Funt, Julian
    - Child of Grace, undated (Box 10)
  - Gagliano, Frank
    - The City Scene (2 Plays: Conerico Was Here to Stay, Paradise Gardens East), 1965 (Box 10)
    - The Commedia World of Lafcadio B (2 copies), undated (Box 10)
    - Conerico Was Here to Stay, 1965 (Box 10)
    - Congo Square (2 copies) (musical), undated (Box 10)
    - Father Uxbridge Wants to Marry, undated (Box 10)
    - Night of the Dunce (2 copies), undated (Box 10)
    - The Nine Pickups of Jeremy Chester, 1969 (Box 10)
    - Paradise Gardens East, 1965 (Box 10)
    - The Private Eye of Hiram Bodoni, 1969, undated (Box 10)
    - The Resurrection of Jackie Cramer (musical), undated (Box 10)
    - The Total Immersion of Madeleine Favorini, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Gallagher, Mary
    - Baseball Sketch, undated (Box 10)
    - Buddies, undated (Box 10)
  - Garrison, John
    - My Dear Descendant, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Gelber, Jack
    - The Connection, 1957 (Box 11)
  - Gerber, Ella and Richardson, Howard
    - The Idols and the Prey
      See: Richardson, Howard, Box 25
  - Gerolmo, Frank M.
    - Dealer's Choice, undated (Box 11)
    - Magio's Cigar Store, undated (Box 11)
  - Gibson, William
    - A Cry of Players, 1954 (Box 11)
    - Dinny and the Witches, 1953 (Box 11)
  - Gilsenan, Nancy Paul
    - Beloved Sissy, undated (Box 11)
  - Giunta, Aldo
    - La Salon, undated (Box 11)
    - The Legacies of Blood, undated (Box 11)
    - Observer's Notes on the Production of "The Little Foxes" at Lincoln Center, undated (Box 11)
    - The Partnership (3 copies), undated (Box 11)
    - The Pink Palace, undated (Box 11)
  - Goforth, Frances and Richardson, Howard
    - Off the Record
  - Goldemberg, Rose Leiman
    - Love One Another, undated (Box 11)
    - Marching as to War, 1972 (Box 11)
    - The Rabinowitz Gambit, undated (Box 11)
    - Rites of Passage, undated (Box 11)
  - Golder, Michael
    - The Square Root of Three, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Goldman, James and Goldman, William
    - Blood, Sweat, and Stanley Poole, undated (Box 11)
  - Goldman, James
    - For Love Alone, 1959 (Box 11)
    - Juan, 1957 (Box 11)
    - Step Right Up, 1955 (Box 12)
    - They Might Be Giants, 1962 (Box 12)
    - Time and Time Again, 1956 (Box 12)
    - Two N's for Nonsense, undated (Box 12)
  - Goldman, William
    - Blood, Sweat, and Stanley Poole
      See: Goldman, James, Box 11
  - Goldsmith, Gloria
    - Friday Dinner on Middle Neck Road, undated (Box 12)
  - Gordon, George N. and Saffron, Robert
    - Cellini Came from My Town
      See: Saffron, Robert, Box 25
  - Gordon, Richard
    - The Bulldog and the Bear, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Granick, Harry
    - Adam Keller, undated (Box 12)
    - The Guilty, undated (Box 12)
    - Witches' Sabbath, undated (Box 12)
  - Gray, Simon
    - The Common Pursuit, undated (Box 12)
  - Graves, Will
    - Harmony House, undated (Box 12)
  - Green, William M. and Turner, Dennis
    - Nell (musical), undated (Box 12)
  - Greenberg, Edward
    - In the Beginning, undated (Box 12)
    - Ring Around the Rosy, undated (Box 12)
    - Rosensweig, F. C., undated (Box 12)
  - Greendale, Alexander
    - The Castle, undated (Box 12)
  - Greenfeld, Josh
    - Clandestine on the Morning Line, undated (Box 12)
    - Tiger!, 1953 (Box 12)
  - Greenwald, Sheila
    - The Wedding War, undated (Box 12)
  - Gregg, Jess
    - The Outside World, undated (Box 12)
    - Reflections in a Broken Mirror, undated (Box 12)
    - The Ruins by Moonlight, undated (Box 12)
    - A Sea Shell, undated (Box 12)
  - Grinstead, Robert
    - The Gift of Mountains, undated (Box 12)
    - Something Nice for Spring, undated (Box 12)
  - Griscom, Lloyd and McGowan, Jack
    - Tenth Avenue
      See: McGowan, Jack, Box 21
  - Gross, Marthe
    - Speak with Demons, undated (Box 12)
  - Guare, John
    - A Day for Surprises, 1965 (Box 13)
    - To Wally Pantoni, We Leave a Credenza, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Hailey, Oliver
    - Child's Play, undated (Box 13)
    - First One Asleep, Whistle, undated (Box 13)
    - Hey You, Light Man!, undated (Box 13)
    - Love...Love...Love, undated (Box 13)
    - The Picture, undated (Box 13)
    - Who's Happy Now?, undated (Box 13)
  - Hamburger, Richard
    - Family Face, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Hammil, Joel
    - The Amiable Devil, undated (Box 13)
    - The Salt Box, undated (Box 13)
  - Harrington, Laura
    - The Listener, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Harris, Andrew B.
    - Tausk, 1971 (Box 13)
  - Harvey, James
    - The Night Brigid Mullaney Left Home, undated (Box 13)
    - The Ocean Out Front, undated (Box 13)
  - Hauptman, William
    - The Durango Flash (2nd Draft), 1977 (Box 13)
  - Haussamen, Crane
    - Abide with Me, undated (Box 13)
  - Havoc, June
    - I, Said the Fly, 1972 (Box 13)
  - Helfer, Richard